all right finally got it hello everyone
welcome back to a product review where
today we're going to be reviewing a
soldering iron splash heating gun it is
a Baku BK 601 D so and I'm just going to
remove a bit of the personal information
and we'll get to unbox the whole thing
from the ebay box all the way to the
insides so there's the big box we're
gonna think in there is that and open it
up and that's going to reveal a smaller
box note that says hello thanks for or
thanks for ordering from us on eBay we
hope you enjoy your new product I hope I
will if everything is ok take a moment
to lead us to leave us positive feedback
and 5-star rating well I'm definitely
gonna do that feedback is very important
to us and we would like to continue to
offer outstanding products prices and
customer service if you have any queries
about your item please contact us on
eBay or Nydia at budget electronics that
CA and we will do our best to assist you
oh isn't that nice anyways
here it is okay so it is a breathless
hot air SMD rework station that's the
first time I'm gonna have a rework
station here let's open it up you got an
instruction book who needs instruction
books I'll probably regret this in five
minutes
I'm upping this off nice little
packaging we have our heat gun when
they're here we have some sort of a
bracket I think this goes with a heat
gun when you attach it what is this ah
yes this is where your soldering iron
gets part and it also comes in with a
pad so you get to clean it a bit too
while you're at it we have B soldering
iron on it so there's this rubber yet
you might want to pump that out nice and
pointy out and it plugs in via this
weird connector but its proprietary what
do you expect
of course it's bukku does it tell you
the wattage probably not what's this a
piece of metal bracket a little thing to
screw and whatever this thing is let's
bring out oops some I believe these are
heat heating gun assemblies where you
put that at the very end of your heat
gun to concentrate the heat even more
let's pop this out
get rid of the box bigger box one thing
is the heat gun is hardwired this is how
you plug it in it is a two problem not
three and now let's see okay we got some
cautions make sure the handle keep on we
make sure the handle keep on the holder
before connected to the power if you can
make sense of that that's typical
Chinese I guess this machine is designed
for large air flow please use the big
nozzle when the air volume is more than
five files avoid reflux to damaged
heating device okay please don't knock
the handle when using comma no space to
prevent damage the heating devices
please wait until the fan stops then
unplug it to switch off the power and
unplug it if there is long time no
operation Chinese never fail alright
anyways what we got here is let's see
our on and off switch for the soldering
iron on our on and off switch for the
heating gun the SMD rework which it goes
up and down we have the amount of air
flow from one all the way up to eight
and we have the temperature which is
from 200 degrees Celsius all the way up
to 480 or 392 to 868 96 so yeah you do
not want to crank this all the way up to
do some soldering job on your
motherboard or electronics unless you do
desire to put them on fire
I have some sort of rubber feet yeah
sort of
that doesn't seem to move too much it is
a 120-volt 8 amps that's what it says it
pushes okay and of course we I believe
this is a little screw for fuse in case
if it blows but that's enough of that
let's see if it works ok when you go
ahead and mount that clip under mount
the thing on the side first I figured
out the hard way damn it
like so clip in first right here thing
could be a bit of a it's best if
you have a magnified screwdriver that
can help you draw a lot more just start
the threads first now we have it done
flip it upside down and not the stupid
thing first make sure make sure that
your heat gun goes on and that the white
side faces upwards your machine not
downwards because if that happens it's
not gonna stick too well it still sticks
but I don't know the drop could be
better this at least you get a firm one
just yeah you got the point okay right
side is done you can put this on the
left if you want to but I prefer to have
it on the right
okay so I didn't manage to figure out
yeah okay so I didn't manage to figure
out how what the heck these things do
and the instruction book really doesn't
do much as for me to explain I could
look it up on the internet but so far I
just want to know if it works properly
and for the heat gun I'm going to use
the slow degrade ma the slowly degrading
tip that goes and shoots concentrated
hot air instead of the one that just
goes BAM so hopefully they'll be good
and the one I'm talking about that goes
BAM is this one right here so see how's
this one slowly degrades well that's
what I want and I'm just gonna throw
that in the box
just to make sure I don't lose anything
and I will be ready hopefully I don't
set anything on fire oh I get it
this controls the soldering iron and
this controls the heat gun and as far as
I know the heat gun goes all the way to
450 which is a little more than 800
Fahrenheit that is scary
that's the thing okay looks like we got
a little bit of a magnet so it's not on
until I pick it up that's it
[Applause]
know what's going on
probably thought about putting that
thing in first mmm let's go ahead and
turn it off okay so they've got our tool
set up so now the airflow is at zero we
got our temperature I'll get it down to
a hundred that's the minimum and the
highest is 450 which goes around a
little over 800 thorough night so it's a
great tool if you want to cook your
chicken but I don't recommend that and
then I'll be able to test the 200
degrees on the air gun and 200 degrees
on the soldering iron for the soldering
needs
so hopefully this thing will be good and
at the same time I'm going to use there
is good old heat gun just to make sure
if my temperatures are set properly so
temperatures are in room temperature so
let's get started yeah so let's just
strive to rip this off in the wall it
went pretty bad so I'll try to see if I
can melt it and I can try it again
so set the temperature should be at
around 100 450 set the air at around 5
and you have to pick it up the air
intake on the right are at the bottom so
hold it in the middle in order to keep
well the best there for air flow
possible now I have it like this I'm
gonna go ahead and lower it down and see
when the effects are taking the care and
now that we get to see the effects going
down down down down down down whoo
this thing will subtract it to it yeah
look at that I managed to fix it mm-hmm
pretty hot well not boiling hot but it's
hot so now let's try a new piece around
here oh nothing something oh yeah we get
to see something here here
yeah it's getting there yeah stand on
this side
oh yeah we get to see the difference
whoo
try the temperature we have 33 degree
tip 68 86 I don't want to milk my tip
either but so eighty six point three
degrees Celsius come on let's try it
again
one more time
[Applause]
oh now we're reading a hundred and ten
degrees or 230 point two Fahrenheit I
don't know if you'll read it they'll
take my word for it let's see if I
didn't damage it yeah yeah looks like I
did some damage apparently now my room
is at 65 degrees and it's going down
down down oh
maybe not the best idea after all what
is going down so I'll do it a break but
it definitely the temperature definitely
seems to be doing the trick but what
about the metal part that's alright yeah
it's off okay so now we got this up now
we're gonna try to set it up at around
150 it's gonna wait you gotta wait for
that flashing dot at the bottom right
it'll tell you that it's ready so now
we're gonna go ahead
there's two spend here I'm gonna try to
see if I can unbend it huh huh we're
getting a nun bended oh nice look
managed to fix it somehow woohoo yep 150
degrees will do the trick
easy holy
crank it update now we're full blast
let's see where are we going to get a
reaction
about 3 inches getting something
it is concentrated blow so yeah as soon
as you hear the you keep it if you put
it right right next to it definitely
it's gonna do something okay it looks
like we're good with that oh I never
thought I'd do this but crank it all the
way up to 450 well this is getting hot
holy are you gonna burn something
sorry
wolf something's burning oh
yes knowing their holy crap I scorched
it that black stuff isn't supposed to be
here oh yeah you want to bake your
chicken go right ahead I ain't doing
that so now it's going down and
temperature wait until it goes there of
course you want to keep your
temperatures as low as possible in order
to keep your heat at heating element MA
intact because when it breaks you have
to open the whole thing up and change
the heating element and I'm not sure how
that'll do but slowly but surely it's
going there yeah I'm gonna crank it up
to 150 so wait for the flashing dot boom
we're done so now we're gonna try
melting some soldering iron let it of
course I'd like to keep my lead-free you
know intact let's see so 150 good enough
I'm pretty sure this is not good enough
it starts at 200 so how about if we try
to 15
No
okay so we got the flashing dot let's
see
well it is scorching it but nothing yet
hard as a rock going up to 250
[Music]
let's see
come on melt
uh-uh yeah yeah it's melting yeah we're
going there
and we got a tip melted nice so we can
do some work with it with the PCBs and
all that perfect that's what I like now
I'm just gonna go ahead and put this on
its stand which put it on standby
temperatures are decreasing and I'm
going to use a bit of an IDE wire and
we're done this my heat gun damaged no
we're back to 25 whew nice okay so now
turn that off turn this on this is our
red bulb this will teach you well it'll
tell you when it's ready so I want to
have it at around 200 it doesn't tell
you my bad
or maybe ah has to go off or on oh okay
so when it's blinking
I mean this thing there's no way this
thing heats up that fast there's no way
now this thing heats up that fast we're
at 34 okay so it's blinking to tell you
that it's heating up and it's gonna stay
solid I believe when it'll be ready 300
degree test getting more results oh oh I
got it I got the whole thing sweet okay
that's all nice and dandy but can we
repair the poor wire hmm so I've got the
wire right here you got a bit of solder
let's see what's gonna happen cleaned it
up the best I could
mmm just taking it nice taking something
it's not taking the whole thing and it's
probably got some dirt but it is taking
some so that's good yeah
most wires your 3d but at least I did
get some this is cool right there you're
bathing somewhere just with the dirty
wire and it looks like it's not gonna
happen so a bit here on the shiny side
but the rest nope but they do have to
say this soldering iron is pretty
freakin great I mean yeah if you want to
make some you know high-end tech stuff
in diggin Anakin's or whatever you need
something bigger of course but for
someone like me who wants a bit of basic
hole miller onyx repair this will do the
trick just fine so I'm gonna go ahead
and wrap things up get out of them get
this mess done and we'll call it a day
so there it is this is a little piece of
toy that I call the Baku 601 D it's
pretty damn versatile for what I've seen
a great starter kit especially like for
me which I have never dealt with the
heat gun before but I do feel confident
that I shouldn't have any problems
however on an upcoming episode there's a
del GX 270 that's coming up and despite
my best effort it did not
well it wasn't able to remove the
capacitor successfully now it that I
can't really blame that little piece of
technology has in a piece of heat
technology anyways because my main
soldering iron could not do the job as
well sometimes I wonder what the hell
does they'll use like melted cast iron
cast iron I don't know I don't get it
sometimes they come off like a charm
sometimes they don't come off at all I
was able to get two of them off with the
heat gun and that it'll help with the
soldering iron I was able to replace one
no problem but the rest just used to
budge so looks like we got after Jerry
Jerry rigged something for that but
overall this product is a 9 out of 10
what up would've liked would have been a
digital thermometer for the soldering
iron and maybe a better instruction
manual I mean what kind of broken
English is this even myself my english
ain't perfect but for crying out loud
but those are two minor little things
I'm not gonna you know complain about it
it's the same thing it tells you when
it's ready as in one flash instead of
two but you also have to make sure your
room is in a comfortable temperature I
mean if you're trying to use this when
it's five degrees outside this could be
why also I had issues with my board
because it was 16 degrees in my room
when I tried to fix it instead of
letting my my room warm up but such
wasn't the case so if you got any
questions comments anything I've
overlooked or not looked at this
particular little toy or if you have one
of these and will like
share your feedback or your experience
with it please feel free to leave a
comment down below and of course until
next time stay bold and take care thanks
for watching
[Music]
there's something I know a Kleenex box
is that fire you don't need a thousand
degrees so let's tackle the white stuff
no I got it stuck and there's nothing
that takes on
oh ow ow ow ow yeah I wasn't too smart
we are getting a bit of scorch that's
good enough to be patient I guess that
girl it is a heat gun I'm not supposed
to have a heat gun blowing as hardcore
as a hair dryer we are getting some
scorching all it's scorching I'm gonna
crank it up to 315
something's green oh it's burning
from the back oh yeah
okay well I'm not going to go ahead and
create a real fire
and have somebody beat me with a toaster